<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Getting Started Guides</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Getting Started Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Including a README with your project</title>
      <link>/guides/writingreadme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Oct 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/writingreadme/</guid>
      <description>What is a README? This is a file that is named README, that usually resides in the root of your project directory. This name comes from the command Read me. as in the situation of handing a project off to another developer and writing a memo to them that should be read first before the source code.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction to build tools</title>
      <link>/guides/buildtools/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Sep 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/buildtools/</guid>
      <description>What is a build tool? GNU Make  Makefile   Apache Maven  Maven Project  Maven Commands Creating a Maven project from Scratch Explaining the pom.xml configiguration file Project File structure Compile and Run   Collaborating on a Maven project   Choosing a Build tool Links  What is a build tool?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with SSH</title>
      <link>/guides/ssh/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/ssh/</guid>
      <description>Getting started with SSH  What is SSH?  What is an SSH Client? When would you use SSH?     SSH by terminal  How do I ssh in terminal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Github Pages</title>
      <link>/guides/githubpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/githubpages/</guid>
      <description>What is Github Pages? How to make your home page When you use GitHub pages, you can access your website at the url http://username.github.io and the underlying files would be found in your repository, which can be found at url pattern ttp://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting started with Git</title>
      <link>/guides/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/git/</guid>
      <description>Git Version control systems are used in managing revision control of project artifacts, and maintaining a history of changes to each artifact. Artifacts can include documents, source code, and much more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java Collections Framework</title>
      <link>/guides/jcf/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/jcf/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This description is taken straight from Oracle&amp;rsquo;s Java Documentation page.
 The Java platform includes a collections framework. A collection is an object that represents a group of objects (such as the classic Vector class).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Java 8</title>
      <link>/guides/java/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/java/</guid>
      <description>1Intro The CIS department at Brooklyn College officially supports Java 8. This means that Java courses are taught adhering to this version. Using later versions such as Java 11 is perfectly find for most instances, there may be some minor differences with certain classes and methods or certain version specific-quirks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File naming conventions</title>
      <link>/guides/filenames/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/filenames/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Common File extensions  Introduction In the day to day work of programming, one often finds that a large fraction of time is spent looking for certain files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started Guides</title>
      <link>/page/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/page/</guid>
      <description>By way of introduction to some of the useful things, this section is provided with some short pages to give a brief introduction.
Pages in this section include:
 Java SDK 8 Java Collections Framework Regular Expressions Build Tools (Apache Maven) Version Control (Git) GitHub Pages Travis CI Markdown Files (Mastering Markdown, GitHub Flavored Markdown Spec)  </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
