<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>git on Getting Started Guides</title>
    <link>/categories/git/</link>
    <description>Recent content in git on Getting Started Guides</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/categories/git/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Github Pages</title>
      <link>/guides/githubpages/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/guides/githubpages/</guid>
      <description>What is Github Pages? #  This is a feature provided by GitHub where you can host websites directly from your GitHub repository. These websites are typically static files, meaning there is no database no backend. For example, this website is hosted on GitHub Pages, it was built with a static site generator.
To find out more, go to https://pages.github.com
How to create your home page (easy way) #  When you use GitHub pages, you can access your website at the url http://username.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Version Control Systems</title>
      <link>/Version-Control/versioncontrol/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Mar 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Version-Control/versioncontrol/</guid>
      <description>Git #  Version control systems are used in managing revision control of project artifacts, and maintaining a history of changes to each artifact. Artifacts can include documents, source code, and much more.
Motivations for Source Version Control
 Keeping track of code Storing versions of code changes Restoring previous versions Reviewing work history Collaborating in a group Backup There are two main approaches to version control management systems. That is, they can either be centralized, or decentralized repositories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>File naming conventions</title>
      <link>/Version-Control/filenames/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2020 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/Version-Control/filenames/</guid>
      <description>Introduction #  In the day to day work of programming, one often finds that a large fraction of time is spent looking for certain files. One of the wise adages with managing an assortment of files is to provide an organization scheme to make it easier to find what you need again. It not only helps you as the maintainer, but also helps your reader(s)** and collaborator(s) as well. This is a good habit to devleop before you find yourself managing hundreds of files.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
